<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of the Company of Vintners, and other retaylors of wines.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 2KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B18655</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888572</idno>
  <idno type="VID">190437</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240899744</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1051B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide L.R.305.a.7.[7]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231108</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888572</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888572e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B18655)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 190437)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C21:2[38])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of the Company of Vintners, and other retaylors of wines.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Publication information from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Wine and wine making --  Taxation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="appeal">
            <pb facs="tcp:190437:1"/>
            <head>The <hi>CASE</hi> of the Company of <hi>VINTNERS,</hi> and other Retaylors of Wines.</head>
            <p>THE Vintner or Retaylor cannot carry on his Trade with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out having two years Stock upon his Hands, for that few Persons will drink <hi>French</hi> Wines till it hath been Ten Months Imported.</p>
            <p>The Stock now in the several Retaylors Hands is at least 30000 Tuns though less Imported this Year than in any one Year within this five Years, above two thirds whereof was Imported at least Twelve Months since before any thoughts of a War with <hi>France.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The whole Stock upon a moderate Computation does lye the Retaylors in Twelve Pence the Quart one with another, there be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Four Pence a Quart paid to the King for his Duty.</p>
            <p>The Retaylors Charge of Lees, Leakage, Cellerage, House-Rent, Servants Wages, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> was ever look'd upon to be so great that he was always allowed to sell at a third peny more then the Wines cost him from the Merchant.</p>
            <p>That should a Clause now be added to the Bill for prohibiting of <hi>French</hi> Commodities to enjoyn the Retaylors to sell the Stock of Wines now in their Hands at Twelve Pence the Quart (the Price they cost) for the first Year, and afterwards at Six Pence the Quart (being half the price they cost) it will ruine and destroy many hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Families who now do contribute considerably towards the support of the Government by paying of Taxes, Quartering of Soldiers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And if the Retaylors be ruined, the Kings Revenue will be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treamly prejudiced, for all the Retaylors in <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Wales</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept the Free <hi>Vintners</hi> of <hi>London,</hi> do draw by License from the Crown at an Annual Rent, but will not be able to pay the same in Case they be constrained to sell their Goods for less than they cost, and so that part of the Revenue will be in great part lost.</p>
            <p>All that is desired, is, That the Parliament would be pleased to Grant the Retaylors a Convenient time to dispose of their Stocks at a Moderate Gain, which they Humbly Conceive will no ways pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote or advance the <hi>French</hi> Interest.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>